我叫梅林达·戈登
My name is Melinda Gordon.
我结了婚  住在一个小镇上
I'm married, I live in a small town,
经营一家古董店
and I own an antique shop.
我也许和你相似
I might be just like you.
但当我还是小姑娘时
Except that from the time I was a little girl,
我就能同亡者交流
I knew that I could talk to the dead.
没事的  亲爱的
It's all right, honey.
祖母称他们为地缚灵
Earthbound spirits, my grandmother called them.
他们在人间滞留  因为他们有未了的心愿
They're stuck here because they have unfinished business with the living
他们找我寻求帮助
and they come to me for help.
讲述我的故事  就是讲述他们的故事
In order to tell you my story, I have to tell you theirs.
救救我
Help me.
能救我出去吗
Can you get me out of here?
谁能听见我说话吗
Can anybody hear me?
我能听到
I can hear you.
我知道你的秘密
And I know your secret.
什么秘密
What secret?
童心不改的秘密
That you are seriously in touch with your inner child.
怎么说呢  我很会找乐子
What can I say? Easily amused.
我喜欢你这一点
No, I love that about you.
套上大鞋子  红鼻头  我就可以扮小丑
You know, large shoes, big, red nose, and I'm all set.
内德去哪了
Where did Ned go?
胡迪尼[魔术大师]
Hey, Houdini.
出来露个面如何
How about making an appearance?
你说过我不用留在这儿
You said I wouldn't have to stay.
但我也说了
Yeah. I also said
你得给我个合适的理由
That you would have to explain why.
我得赶明天的数学作业  非常重要
I have a really important math project due tomorrow.
但我今天也很需要人帮忙
I was actually counting on another pair of hands today.
这样吧
Will these do?
我留下
I'll stay.
希望你不介意
I hope you're not upset.
只要你愿意
As long as you're ok with it.
棒极了  谢谢老妈  谢谢梅林达
Cool. thanks, mom. thanks, Melinda.
要是他这次还只得个C
If he even cracks a "c" on this project,
我就让他好看
I can live with getting a "c" on my parenting.
那么  我该做些什么
So, what do you need me to do?
关门
Close up.
我们去采购
We're going shopping.
我在这儿住了20年
I lived at this place for the last 20 years
从没想过要离开
I never thought I'd have to leave.
生意很差吗
Business is that slow?
易趣网流行之后  就很惨淡了
Ever since ebay dead as a doornail.
你也可以在网上卖啊
Well, you could sell your stuff online, too,
或者
Or,
雇个人帮忙
Get somebody else to do it
你就可以舒服地在家做生意了
and sell your stuff from the comfort of your own home.
才不  我喜欢人多热闹
Nah. I'm too much of a people person.
讨价还价多爽啊
I'd miss talking to folks.
梅林达  过来看看这个
Melinda, you have to look at these.
瞧见了吧
See what I mean?
我好像没把这些摆出来
I didn't know that I had put those out.
这些不卖吗
Are these not for sale?
不不  卖  清仓处理
No. no, they're for sale. everything must go.
我知道你为何不愿离开它们了
I can understand why you wouldn't want to part with them.
多漂亮
They're gorgeous.
表面是手绘的
Handpainted on the front.
是圣诞节饰品吗
Are they christmas ornaments?
只要你喜欢  什么节日都能用
Oh, well, could be,or whatever you like.
如果你不要
If you don't get these,
那我就买了自己要
I'm gonna get them for the store myself.
好吧  我买了
Ok, I'll take them.
你眼光真好  迪莉娅
You have a good eye, Delia.
要采购  欢迎随时找我
You can go shopping with me anytime you want.
别后悔哦
Oh, you're gonna be sorry you said that.
鬼语者  第二季  第4集
自闭其中
把它们摆哪里好
So where do you want me to put these?
不急着摆出来
Oh, we don't have to do that now.
你开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
卖出第一套房子后  我就再没这么兴奋过
I haven't been this jazzed since I sold my first house.
这感觉太怀旧了
Seems like a thousand years ago.
千万别告诉内德
And please don't tell Ned.
我要他觉得  我替他给你帮忙
I want him to think that covering his hours
是做出了天大的牺牲
Was a huge sacrifice for me.
这书架不太稳
You know what, I think this shelf isn't level.
你该在这条腿下垫块木头
You wanna put a piece of wood right underneath this leg.
也许
You know,
我们该暂时把饰品留在盒子里
Maybe we could just keep the ornament in the box for now.
POP  购物的目的
P.O.P. "point of purchase. "
就是要摆在醒目之处
You always wanna put some out front
让所有人都看到
Where everyone can see them.
我会考虑
I'll think about that.
这就对了
That's the point.
不要光想  买才重要
You don't wanna think. You just wanna buy.
把它们收起来  好吗
Can you just put them back, please?
当然
Sure.
我不是那意思
I didn't mean to it.
只是有时  到了新货
It's just sometimes when I have new things,
我喜欢先收着
I like to hold off on putting them out
直到有合适买主出现
Until I'm really sure where they're going.
我理解
I understand.
梅林达  真的很抱歉
Melinda, I am so sorry.
我有时太忘乎所以了
I just get carried away sometimes.
我也很抱歉  我有点焦躁
Me, too. I guess I'm just a little on edge.
我知道自己当老板不容易
I know it's not easy being your own boss.
我过去也常想能有自己的地方
I used to think that I was gonna open up my own place,
开一家这样的小店
Have a little store like this one.
店名叫"迪莉娅饰品店"
I was either gonna call it Delia's decorations
或"街边收藏馆"
Or the curbside curator.
那为什么没呢
And why didn't you?
我结婚了  生了内德
I got married, I had Ned,
过去的想法
And then the concept of someday
就变得不切实际了
Just becomes a little more abstract.
你怎么会做房地产呢
Uh, how did you get into real estate?
我丈夫过世之后
When my husband died.
我不得不赶紧改变计划
I had to think of a plan "b" in a hurry.
因为小生意来钱太慢
There's no time to grow a small business.
我必须出去赚钱回来  所以
I had to get out there and make some money, so
我取得了地产执照
Got my real estate license.
你能买些报纸来吗
Could you grab some newspapers
或者看看房地产广告
And maybe check for estate sales?
当然  没问题
Sure. No problem.
越快越好  以免售罄
As soon as you can, before they run out.
要我顺路给你带些什么吗
On my way, want anything else?
不用  谢谢
No. Thanks.
好的
Ok.
你是谁
Who are you?
你怎么了
What's going on?
发生什么事了
What's happening?
告诉我  我可以帮你
Talk to me. I can help.
住手
Stop it.
别这样
Don't do that.
快停下
Just please stop it.
求你
Please.
住手
Stop it!
Stop!
求你了
Please.
你能看见我吗
Can you see me?
这么说你能看见他  听到他
So you can see and hear this ghost,
但他却看不见  也听不到你
But he can't see or hear you?
是啊  太悲哀了
Yeah. How's that for a cruel twist of fate?
也许他又聋又瞎
Maybe this ghost is deaf and blind.
他好像被困住了
It's like he's trapped here,
受那些圣诞饰品的折磨
Being tormented by these christmas ornaments.
不是每个人都喜欢节日
Not everybody likes the holidays.
他一定想摆脱它们
He's definitely trying to get rid of them.
它们仿佛有生命  能呼吸似的
It's like they're alive, breathing.
我从见过这种情形
I've never seen anything like it.
东西在哪儿
Where are they now?
我还以为被你藏起来了
Well, I was hoping the answer was hidden,
比如在店里某个隐蔽的角落
You know, deeply away somewhere in the store.
真漂亮
Well, they're pretty.
真希望你也能看见
I wish you could see this.
我想抱你
Let me hold you.
我能碰你吗
Can't I touch you?
不
No!
住手
Stop it!
别管我
Leave me alone!
撑住
Come on.
保持呼吸
Keep breathing.
站好了  没事了
Stand up. You're all right.
刚才怎么了
What happened?
我还想问你呢  你刚才晕了
You tell me.you just blacked out there for a while.
我感到很害怕  又很愤怒
I felt scared and really angry.
让我难以承受
It was overwhelming.
坐下休息会儿
Maybe you should sit down.
不  不行  我想出去走走
No, I don't think I can. I should walk it off.
你看到东西了
Did you see anything?
是的  有两个人在打架
Yeah, I did. 2 people hitting each other
有什么冲突
And some kind of fight.
好吧  得弄走这个鬼魂
Ok, I want this ghost out of here.
如果他想毁了这些饰品
If the ghost wants to destroy these ornaments,
又不能自己解决
He can't do it himself,
火烧是毁掉木制品的最好方法
Fire is the best way that I know to destroy something made of wood.
我替他完成  他就能超度了
If I do it for him, he can cross over.
他走了吗
Is he gone?
是的
Yes.
好吧
All right.
进屋吧
Come on.
我饿死了
Oh, I am so hungry.
它们又回来了
They're back.
还有他
So is he.
佩恩教授
Professor Payne?
Professor Payne.
走开
Go away!
我改主意了  今天不接待学生
I changed my mind! No student office hours today!
我不是学生
I'm not a student.
我是梅林达·戈登  你之前帮过我
It's Melinda Gordon. You helped me before.
我该提醒自己
Note to self
别再帮人
Stop helping people.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
在撞到头之前  我正在找午餐
Well, before I hit my head, I was looking for my lunch.
应该在一个纸袋里
It's in a paper bag.
自带午餐  这不像你啊
Brown bagging lunch. That doesn't sound like you.
戈登女士  好吧
Ms. Gordon. All right.
你又找我什么事
What do you have for me, huh?
一堆你已经知道答案的
Bunch of ambiguous questions that
模棱两可的问题
You probably already know the answers to?
过奖了
You give me too much credit.
哪里  岂止
Maybe not enough credit. hmm?
在你的研究中  有遇到过
In your studies, have you ever come across a situation
鬼魂能变出某件实体的情况吗
Where a spirit can make an object appear in our world?
物质化
Materialization?
也许吧  但我是指
I guess. what I'm talking about is
那样东西  不仅鬼魂能看到并碰触到
An object that the spirit can see and touch and that
我们也能
We can see and touch, too.
希望是珠宝或钞票
Let's hope it's jewelry and cash then, huh?
有或没有
Yes or no?
我听说过  但我不信
Look, I've heard of it, but I don't believe it.
为什么
And why not?
因为我不信鬼魂之说
Because I don't believe in ghosts!
你怎能研究这个  却又不信它呢
How can you study this stuff and not believe in it?
我不研究鬼怪  戈登小姐
I don't study the stuff, Ms. Gordon.
我研究的是产生信仰的根源
I study people's need to believe in the stuff,
就像我面前的你
People like you standing in front of me,
看上去
Looking
秀色可餐
Looking beautiful.
香水味芬芳诱人
And smelling delicious is what that perfume,
是法国货吗
Is that french?
让我闻闻
Let me smell it.
好吧  我们假设一下
Ok, let's just assume for a minute
鬼魂真实存在  并能移动物体
That spirits exist and they can move objects.
这叫"幻象"
Yeah. They called apports.
源自法语"Apporter"  表示"带来"
It's from the french word apporter. It means "to bring. "
带来什么
Bring what?
比香水厉害多了
More of that perfume you're wearing,
老实说  这味儿让人兴奋
'cause seriously, it's making me bananas.
开玩笑呢  也许是真的
I'm kidding. Unless I'm not.
好吧  开玩笑的
Ok, I'm kidding.
带来"透彻"
Um, it brings clarity,
深究其意  脱离字面
Deeper understanding, aside from the literal,
有种解释说  "幻象"是
You know, interpretation that an apport is
亡灵向活人传达其意
Sent from beyond to the living,
也许是要揭示非常重要的事情
Maybe it's a manifestation of something that's so important,
具有很强的象征性
You know, something really symbolic.
那么  如果鬼魂不能说话
So, if a ghost couldn't talk,
他们可能会变出东西
They would maybe make an object appear
以此进行交流
As a way of communicating.
这些幻象能自己移动吗
And can these apports move on their own?
没错  猫都能滑水
Yeah, and cats can waterski.
所以它们发光
Is that why they glow?
猫不会发光
Cats don't glow!
-幻象  -我知道你说的幻象
- Apports.  - I know you're talking about apports!
-你吼什么  -我没有吼
- Why are you yelling?!  - I'm not yelling.
我在吼  行了吧
I'm yelling, right?!
我错了
I make that mistake.
抱歉  我只是想区分开
I'm sorry. I tend to disassociate.
真会掩饰
That's an understatement.
你想要什么
What do you want?
你来这干什么
Why are you here?
你家出现幻象了
Do you have an apport at home,
而且还幽幽发着鬼光吗
And it's just glowing with ghostly energy?
要是真的  你干嘛不带来测试一下
Well, if that's true, why don't you bring it in so we can test it?
我怎么会看见幻象
Why would I have an apport?
根本没这回事  都是假的  行了吧
I mean, there's no such thing. It's make believe, right?
你  你嘲笑我
You, you baffle me!
臭娘们
You little minx.
我就知道你会回来
I had a feeling you'd be back.
是吗
Really?
谁是回头客  我一看就知
I know a repeat customer when I see one.
还有些东西剩下
Still got a few things left.
还有饰品吗
Any more ornaments?
没了  你全都买走了
No, don't worry. You've got the only ones.
能告诉我  你从哪进货的吗
I was hoping you could tell me where you got them.
为什么
Why?
万一他们还有呢
In case they have any more.
我看不一定
Well, I doubt that there are.
也是啊  独一无二的
Yeah. Pretty unique.
我不知道它们从哪来的
Well, I don't know where they came from.
如果我知道  会告诉你的
If I did, I'd let you know.
失陪  我要去收拾了
Now, if you excuse me, I gotta get back to my packing.
也许那些饰品是突然冒出来的
Maybe the ornaments just appeared out of nowhere.
什么叫"突然冒出来"
How do you mean "just appeared"?
昨晚  有一套一模一样的饰品
Last night, a set of ornaments just like the ones that you sold me
突然出现在我厨房里
Just appeared on my kitchen table.
看来我没疯
I thought I was going crazy.
你没有
You're not.
我昨天绞尽脑汁回想
I racked my brain trying to remember
是我是从谁那买的
If I picked 'em up from someone yesterday
还是谁落在店里了
Or if I saw someone drop 'em here at the stall.
有没有一个30多岁的男人
What about a man in his midthirties,
棕色短发  胡子拉茬  肤色苍白
Short brown hair, stubble, pale skin,
衣衫褴褛  不太喜欢直视的男子
A little disheveled, doesn't like to look you in the eye?
我尽力回忆  但没有
Shifty I tend to remember, but no, no,
实在没印象
He's not ringing a bell.
如果看到这样的人  我会告诉你
If I see anybody like that, I'll let you know.
拜托了
Please.
梅林达
Melinda,
等等
Wait.
我刚发现这个
I just found this.
我买了
I'll buy it from you.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
你拿着吧  它该属于你
Yyou take it. I think you should have it.
好吧
Ok.
我需要你用专业知识来帮我找这座房子
I need your real estate expertise to find this house.
这房子听起来不错
It sounds like an amazing house,
但你不记得在哪了
But you don't remember where it is?
我没去过  是一位顾客告诉我的
I've never been. A client of mine told me about it.
他不记得地址了
He can't remember the address?
他不住这附近
He's not from around here.
他想买吗
Is he looking to buy?
有生意做吗
Do I have a shot?
我不知道他是否有能力抵押贷款
I'm not so sure he could swing a mortgage,
但他让我很好奇  我想看看
But he's got me curious. I'd love to see it.
这个网站里面
This is the website that tracks
有本地区所有的物业资料
All of the residential properties in the area.
你可以用我的账户查看
You can go ahead and use my account number
输入尽可能多的细节
And just put in as many details as you can
在数据库里找找
And then search the database
看看能否找到
And see if you find the house.
如果你说服他购买
If you convince him to buy,
就把他带过来吧
Will you steer him my way?
多谢
Thank you.
这鬼魂终于肯和你交流了
Well, at least now the ghost is communicating with you.
对  就像这样
Oh, yeah. We're like this.
他不说话  不看我  完全无视我的存在
He won't talk to me, look at me, or even acknowledge my presence.
你说过  他需要更多时间 来适应死亡
Well, you did say it takes some longer than others to adjust to death.
是的  面对死亡  每人反应都不一
Yeah. everybody deals with death differently.
迪莉娅到现在还没熬出来呢
I think Delia's having a hard time with it.
你告诉她了
Oh, yeah? Did you talk to her?
我想说  但还没找到好时机
I've been meaning to, but I haven't really had the chance.
找到了
That's it.
就是这房子
That's the house.
有人吗
Hello?
有人在家吗
Is anybody home?
有人吗
Hello.
你好
小姐
Miss.
等我一下
Give me a minute.
她还好吗
She ok?
身体无大碍
Physically, she's fine.
她只是非常自闭  不愿讲话
She's just completely withdrawn. she won't talk.
跟某人很像
Sounds like somebody else I know.
她叫克莉斯汀·纳尔逊
The woman's Christine Nelson.
在屋内找到了她的身份证
Found her picture I.D. inside.
那男的
And he's,
他叫丹尼斯·海托华
Well, he was Dennis Hightower.
希望能对你有所帮助
I don't know if that does you any good.
这房子里肯定发生过恐怖的事情
Something terrible must have happened in this house.
还记得我第一次看见的意象吗
I mean, do you remember the first vision I had?
两个人打斗
2 people fighting.
我必须要让他跟我谈谈
I have to get him to talk to me.
你找到他的尸体
Look, you found his body.
也许这样就够了  他可以超度了
Maybe that's all he needed to resolve before he could cross over.
但他还在这
But he's still here.
是的  警察也快来了  所以
Yeah, well, the police will be, too, so...
丹尼斯·海托华
Dennis Hightower.
我知道你的名字  你吃惊吗
Are you surprised that I found out your name?
-你的名字  -梅林达
- Your name?  - Melinda.
真的很高兴见到你
It's really nice to meet you.
一切都会好的
Everything's gonna be ok now.
我们找到了你的尸体  你可以超度了
We found your body.You can cross over.
你只需走进那道光里就行了
All you have to do is go into the light.
丹尼斯  你能看到那道光吗
Dennis, can you see the light?
-你看见一道光   -没有  只有你能看到
- You see the light?  - No. I can't. Only you can.
你还有什么心事吗
Is there something else that you need?
我能帮上你忙的
Something that I can help you with?
告诉我  你出什么事了
Tell me what happened to you.
你出什么事了
What happened to you.
你知道  你已经死了  对吧
You know that you're dead, right?
-对  -谁杀了你
- Right.  - Who did this to you?
-你  你  -你怎么听不懂我说的话
- You. You.  - Why don't you understand me?
听懂我说的话
Understand me.
验尸报告说  丹尼斯似乎是被毒死的
Coroner's report says it looks like dennis was poisoned.
他为什么不告诉我
Why didn't he tell me about that?
也许我该告诉克里斯汀
Maybe I'd be better off if I talked to Christine.
交给警察去说吧
Let the police do that.
他明显是想要我找到她
I mean, he obviously led me to her for a reason.
她也许是他生命中很重要的人
She might be an important part of his life.
也可能是他死亡的重要一部分
She might be an important part of his death.
不  你这么认为
No. You think?
丹尼斯和克里斯汀
Dennis and Christine
也许就是在你的意象里打架的人
might be the 2 people you saw fighting in your vision.
为什么她要毒死丹尼斯
Why would she poison Dennis
又留在尸体旁边
And then stay with the body?
有时内疚感是克制不住的
Guilty don't always run and hide.
也许丹尼斯让你去那房子
Maybe Dennis led you to the house
并不是让你去帮助克里斯汀
not to help christine,
而是找到凶手
But to help you find his killer.
他为什么不超度
Why didn't he cross over?
说不过你  你应该去找克里斯汀
You're right. You should try and talk to Christin.
[康复中心]
你有预约吗
Do you have an appointment?
没有  我来找个病人  克里斯汀·纳尔逊
No. I'm, uh, looking for a patient, Christine Nelson.
仁济医院急诊室说  她转来这里了
The emergency room at Mercy hospital told me that she was taken here.
今早送来的
This morning.
为什么要转移
And why was she moved?
病人太多  床位太少
Too many heads, not enough beds.
如果不是病重  濒死或致命伤的患者
If your condition isn't serious, Life-threatening, or fatal,
就会被转走  跟我来
you get turfed out. Follow me.
克里斯汀  有人来看你了
Christine, you have a visitor.
我们昨天在你的房子里见过
We met yesterday at your house.
我是梅林达·戈登
I'm Melinda Gordon.
我先回去工作了
I should get back to my desk.
我知道警察来过
I know that the police were here
你不想跟他们说
And you wouldn't talk to them.
我不是警察  你告诉我吧
I'm not the police, and I need you to talk to me.
我认识丹尼斯
I knew Dennis.
我知道他是怎么死的
I think I know how he died,
但我想弄清其中缘由
But it would help to know why.
克里斯汀  你听到我说话了吗
Christine, can you hear me?
克里斯汀恢复交流能力
It's gonna take some time before Christine's
可能还需要点时间
communicatmmn skills are back to where they were.
戈登女士  我是希拉里·斯隆医生
Ms. Gordon, Dr. Hillary sloan.
我以为她没有遭受物理伤害
I thought that she didn't suffer any physical damage.
的确没有
She didn't.
但这场突然的变故
But this kind of change
对自闭症患者来说  打击不小
Is a lot for a person with autism to process.
等等  你说克里斯汀患有自闭症
Wait. Did you just say that Christine is autistic?
你现在有时间吗
Do you have a minute?
如你所见  他们喜欢猜谜和游戏
As you can see, they like puzzles and games.
踱步  拍手  来回走动
Pacing, hand flapping, rocking back and forth-
这全是自闭症的典型表现
they are all coping mechanisms for people with autism.
有些高功能自闭症患者
You know, there are high-functioning people with autism
已经能在一定程度上与他人相处
who've learned to behave in a more socially acceptable way.
但大多数都不合群
A lot of them are loners.
他们更喜欢与物相处  而不是人
They relate better to objects than they do to people.
不喜爱说话
They don't like to talk.
也不看对方的眼睛
Or look you in the eye.
他们不遵守我们的社交习惯
They don't follow a lot of our social rules.
丹尼斯也患有自闭症
Dennis is autistic.
克里斯汀和丹尼斯20岁开始就住一起了
Christine and Dennis had lived together since their twenties.
他们是夫妻吗
They were a couple.
是的  他们请了一个保姆  每周来一次
Yes. They had a home-care worker who came over once a week.
除此之外  就只有丹尼斯照顾她
Other than that, Dennis took care of her.
她从哪里弄来的
Where did she get this?
这是我的
Oh. Um, that's mine.
我店里卖这个  她一定是从我包里找到的
I sell those in my store. She must have taken it from my purse.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
-是烤炉  -什么
- It was the oven.  - I'm sorry?
我知道丹尼斯怎么死的了
I know how Dennis died.
等等  如果真是一氧化碳中毒
Wait, if it was carbon monoxide poisoning,
为什么克里斯汀没事
how come Christine wasn't affected?
因为她习惯  回到家后
Because it's her ritual every time she comes home
打开所有的窗户
to open up all the windows.
我看到了
I saw it in a vision.
她不是杀人犯
She's not a murderer.
-女杀人犯  -说得好
- Murderess.  - Touche.
问题是为什么丹尼斯还不走
Question is why is Dennis still here?
我找到了克里斯汀  她很安全  还有什么
I found Christine. She's safe. What more is there?
我倒想知道  为何丹尼斯还是那么自闭
What I wanna know is Why is Dennis still autistic.
他死后  就应该痊愈了  不是吗
If he's dead, he should be cured, right?
理论上说是这样  所有灵魂都是完美的
Mmm, technically, yes. Every soul is perfect.
他们超度时
When they cross over,
所有的缺陷都不会再影响他们
The handicaps they had in life no longer affect them,
但如果他是地缚灵
but if they're earthbound,
它们有时会和以前一样
Sometimes they cling to the familiar.
他们不能忘记过去的自己
They can't let go of who they were.
他也算是回答了你  是吧
He did answer your questions at some point, didn't he?
他学我说话  叫做模仿言语
He's been mimicking me. It's called echolalia.
他通过学你讲话  来让你知道
It's when they echo whatever you say so you know
虽然他们不回答  但是听到你说话了
that they can hear you, even if they can't respond.
就是说  他一直在和你交流
Ok, so all this time, he has been communicating with you,
-只不过是用他的方法  -是的  通过这些装饰品
- ... just in his own way.  - Yes, through the ornaments.
我最后碰过的那个  告诉了我他怎么死的
The last one that I touched showed me how he died.
但愿其中一块饰品能解释他不走的原因
Let's hope the answer to why he's still here is in one of those.
这些东西
These objects,
跟平常的物件没什么两样
They don't vibrate any more or less than your average object.
你一点都看不到  听不到他们的内心吗
And you can't see or hear anything coming from inside them?
看到啥  电影吗
Like what? What, a movie?
我会看到电影吗  还是听到口技
What am I gonna see, a movie? Listen to, show tunes?
这是木头的  跟我脑袋一样
It's wood. It's like my head.
再普通不过了
Lady, it's normal.
它们一点也不普通
There's nothing normal about them.
你朋友说
So your "friend" said
她拿着这些饰品时  能感觉到自己在移动
She felt transported after she held these ornaments?
-是的  -好  我正拿着这些饰品
- Yes.  - Ok. Well, I held these ornaments.
我一动也没动
I'm still here.
你朋友看到这意象是什么时候
What time of day did your friend say she had these visions?
发生时间很重要吗
Why is the time of day important?
当然  如果是快活完后发生的
Well, yeah. If she did it right after happy hour,
-就非常重要   -是的  是很有趣
- I'd say it's very important.  - Yeah, that's real funny.
我以为你至少对此会有职业上的好奇心
I thought you would at least have a professional curiosity about this.
我很好奇
Oh, I'm curious.
我对你很感兴趣
I have a lot of curiosity about you,
特别是你来做什么
About what you're doing here.
我只想知道  你能否从饰品里看到东西
I just wanna know If you can see anything in these ornaments.
梅林达  从你进来开始
Melinda, you haven't touched any of these ornaments
你就没碰过这些饰品   一个也没有
since you've been here, not directly, not one.
我想知道你碰它们时会发生什么
I wanna know what happens when you touch these ornaments.
-我不知道   -我想找出答案
- I don't know.  - Yeah, well, I'd like to find out.
这个  这兔子图案的
This one, the bunny,
比其它饰品的能量更高
Had a higher energy rating than the other ornaments.
当你碰它时  会发生什么
What happens when you touch that guy?
我以为你是个信科学的人
You know, I thought you were a man of science,
你这也太不科学了
And there's nothing scientific about this.
收集经验数据  怎么不科学了
What's more scientific than collecting my own empirical data?
你要呆在这里
You're going to stay here right now, Christine.
我爱你  亲爱的
I love you, sweetie.
不  别  妈妈  不要离开我
No! Stop it!  Mami... Don't leave me!
怎么  发生了什么
What? What happened?
你看见了什么
What did you see?
我看见一个孩子被人从母亲身边带走
I saw a child being taken from her mother.
你说真的吗
Are you telling me the truth?
教授  我只能说  如果我走出这扇门之后
All I can say, professor, if I could walk out of here
发现我们所说的这些都是虚构的
knowing that everything we've talked about was made up,
我就是世上最幸福的女孩
I would be the happiest girl on earth.
等等  灵媒
Wait. Psychometry.
你刚刚说的叫作灵媒
What you're talking about is called psychometry.
就是说  你能通过触碰物件
It's when you get visions or flashes
看到过去发生的事情
of the past from touching these objects.
-有道理  -你见到了  当然信
- That makes sense.  - Easy for you to say.
你能不能对这些饰品做更多试验
Maybe if you did some more tests on the ornaments.
我想在你身上做些试验
I'd like to actually do some tests on you, Melinda.
感谢你的讲解
Thanks for your time.
梅林达  我不是要把你绑手术台上
Melinda, I'm not talking about root canal here.
而是科学的  受控制的试验
I'm talking about very scientific, controlled tests.
这能帮助我们
They could- they can help us.
-我不是实验品  -梅林达  听我说
- I'm not an experiment.  - Melinda, listen.
你若再看到灵媒  过来找我
When you get a chance, just come by.
告诉我更多的事情
Come by and talk to me some more.
这很重要
This is important.
我认为这不止关系到他
I don't think it's about him.
而是他们俩
I think it's about both of them.
对了  那个也卖的
Oh, that's on sale, by the way.
这像是他对两人生活的记忆
It's like it's his memories of their life together,
他怎么死的  初次邂逅的情景
you know, how he died, when he first saw her.
-是的  -无论丹尼斯要什么
- That makes sense. - Well, whatever Dennis wants,
都跟克里斯汀有关
it has something to do with Christine somehow.
真可惜  她不能和你说话
It's too bad she won't talk to you.
也许她对这些饰品有反应
Maybe she'll respond to the ornaments.
我把这些拿到医院去
I thought that I would take them down to the hospital
看能不能达到效果
And see if it could spark anything
我如果现在出发  还能赶上探视时间
Besides, if I leave now, I can still make visiting hours.
好  我想帮你看店  不过
Well, I'd offer to mind the store, but...
没关系  我知道你忙于救活人
it's ok. I know that you're busy saving lives
我忙于救死人
While I'm saving the dead.
-拜  -再见
- Bye. - See ya.
内德今天表现怎样
How'd, uh, Ned do today?
-我提早让他回家了  -真的
- Oh, I sent him home early.  - Really?
-他又犯什么事儿了  -没犯事儿
- What did he do now?  - Oh, no. Nothing.
没事  我关店了
It's fine. It's just I had to close up.
我要去做件事
I have an errand to run.
那我就不耽误你了
Well, don't let me keep you.
他给你添麻烦了就告诉我  好吗
You just let me know if he causes you any trouble, ok?
我最讨厌的就是  明明自己不好受
You know, what I hate is when people ask if you're ok
别人还问我好不好
when you're so obviously not.
是啊  我也讨厌
Yeah. I hate that, too.
所以  你还好吗
So, are you ok?
不  只是
I- no. It's just...
说不清  日子每天都一样
I don't know. It's just been one of those days.
我卖房子卖到吐了
I am so sick of selling houses.
我每溜达一圈
Every time I turn around,
都能遇见新婚夫妇首次买房
There's this new couple buying their house for the first time.
相互争论哪间房作书房  哪间作客厅
They're arguing about where to put the office or the guest room.
不是新婚夫妇  就是初为父母者
And if it's not newlyweds, then it's new parents, and...
讨论哪间房作婴儿房
They're trying to figure out where the baby room goes.
每个人都有自己的生活
Everybody has their whole life ahead of them.
你和查理结婚多久了
How long were you and Charlie married?
有时我感觉我们仍是夫妇
Sometimes it feels like we're still married.
他去世三年了
He's been dead for 3 years now.
我刚刚从悲痛中走出来
I've just been having such a hard time moving on.
内德也很坚强
And Ned's been acting out.
我知道他需要我
I know he needs me,
我也在尽我所能地守着他
And I am doing everything I can to be there for him.
我明白
I understand.
随便了
Anyway-heh.
你还没告诉我你的秘密
Why don't you tell me your secret?
找份喜欢的工作  能帮你转移注意力
Oh, well, having work that you love takes your mind off things.
不过我的工作却恰恰相反
Ah. Well, my work does just the opposite.
也许你该换份新工作
Well, maybe you should try something new.
换什么  脑外科医生  战斗机驾驶员
Like what? Brain surgeon? Fighter pilot?
你应该挑个更有挑战性的
Heh. I was thinking of something even more challenging,
比如
Like...
不如来和我一起工作吧
Why don't you come and work with me?
-什么  -我真的需要人手
- What?  - I need the help really bad,
虽然我付的工钱比不上你的售房佣金
And I can't pay as much as one of your sales commissions,
但却是份稳定的收入
but it's a steady check everyweek.
我想你会喜欢的
And I think you will really like it.
-你说真的  -是的
- You're serious?  - Yeah.
-干嘛  -我真是看不透你
- What?  - I just can't figure you out.
你就像是个
You're like some kind of...
守护天使
Guardian angel or something.
答应我  好好考虑一下
Promise me that you'll at least think about it.
小兔子
Bunny.
树
Tree.
蝴蝶
Butterfly.
蛋糕
Cake.
房子
House.
自行车
Bike.
摇椅
Rocking chair.
这些对你有什么含义  克里斯汀
What do these mean to you, christine?
小兔子带我上学
Bunny took me to school.
她戴一只蝴蝶在颈边
She wore a butterfly around her neck.
她教我骑自行车
She taught me how to ride a bike.
我们坐在房前的树下
We sat under the tree in front of the house.
谁是小兔子
Who is bunny?
谁戴着蝴蝶项链带你去学校
Who wore a butterfly necklace and took you to school?
-她   -她是谁
- She did.  - who is she?
妈妈  她是妈妈
Mommy. Mommy is she.
是她妈妈
It's her mother.
这些饰品象征着她妈妈
These ornaments symbolize mommy to Christine.
这就是你想要我做的吗
Is that what you wanted me to do...
找到克里斯汀的妈妈
Find Christine's mother?
F- find Christine's mother.
是的
I did.
不  不  不  是正面朝上的
Oh, no. No, no, no. They're faceup.
这样放不对
That's- that's the wrong way.
-这是拼图  -这是拼图
- This is a puzzle? - This is a puzzle.
小兔子
Bunny.
这是她母亲
That's her mother?
我想这些是你的
I believe these were meant for you.
你为什么把克里斯汀送走
Why did you give Christine away?
你要知道  克里斯汀出生那时
You have to understand that back when Christine was born,
人们对自闭症了解不多
people didn't know that much about autism.
你能想象你的孩子
Can you imagine having a child
不能看着你或对你微笑吗
that won't look at you or smile,
你能想象你一碰她
A child that starts to cry every time
她就会哭吗
You try to touch her?
我带克里斯汀去看医生
I took Christine to a doctor,
医生说是我的错
And he told me it was my fault.
他说她得自闭症
He said the reason she was autistic was
是因为我这个母亲不称职
Because I was a bad mother.
这太可怕了
That's terrible.
不过  不止说我一个人
Well, I wasn't the only one.
他们管我们叫冷酷的母亲
Said we were refrigerator mothers
因为我们对孩子太冷酷
because we were so cold and frigid
孩子找不到人安慰自己
that our children had no one to turn to for comfort,
于是转而自我封闭
so they turned inside themselves.
所以你让医生带走了她
So you let them take her.
我曾想去看她  但他们不让
I tried to see her, to visit, but they said I couldn't,
他们说  若想让她好起来
Said if she was ever gonna get any better,
我就不能见她
I had to stay away.
她成年后你去看过她吗
Didn't you see her when she was a grown-up?
有过一次
Once.
她和一个年轻人住在一起
She was living with a young man.
他也是自闭症患者
He was autistic, too.
但是死在一次争吵中
But it ended up in a fight...
别管我
Leave me alone!
我看到了那次争吵
I saw that fight.
-什么  -这不重要
- Wh-what? - It's not important.
重要的是
What is important is that
你要再去见克里斯汀
You have to try again with Christine.
她需要你
She needs you.
我的小宝贝  长大了
It's my baby girl, all grown up.
她依然封闭在自己的世界里
She's still in her own little world.
克里斯汀  你妈妈来看你了
Christine, your mother's here to see you.
克里斯汀  我是妈妈
C- Christine, it's-it's mommy.
-真的对不起  -真的对不起
- I am so sorry. - I am so sorry.
没关系  她听着呢  告诉她你的感受
It's ok. She hears you. Just tell her how you feel.
她没有怨恨你
She's not holding a grudge,
我保证  她没生你的气
and I promise that she is not angry with you.
我是否在这儿
Doesn't make one bit of difference to her
对她丝毫没有影响
Whether I'm here or not.
不是这样的
That- that is not true.
说"爱需要耐心"  说"爱需要耐心"
S- say, "love is patient. " Say, "love is patient. "
你需要耐心些
You just have to be patient.
亲爱的
Sweetheart...
莉斯  莉斯  等等
Liz, Liz, wait.
我根本不该来
This was a mistake.
她现在最需要你
She needs you now more than ever.
我的孩子不需要我  从来不需要
My child doesn't need me. She never has.
谁都需要母亲
Everyone needs their mother.
可再也不可能爱我  梅林达
But she will never be able to love me, melinda.
她甚至不知道什么是爱
She doesn't even know what love is.
你错了  克里斯汀是爱你的
That's not true. Christine loves.
她只是不知道如何表达
She just doesn't know how to show it.
她男朋友  一直在教他如何表达
Her boyfriend, he was teaching her how.
爱是教不会的
You can't teach somebody how to love.
感受不到就是感受不到
They either feel it, or they don't.
-问她  -你爱克里斯汀吗
- Ask her.  - Do you love christine?
我想爱  但是
I want to, but...
我不懂如何单方面地爱
I don't know how if she can't love me back.
那你就该先让她感受到你的爱
Well, then you have to show her love first,
哪怕她不知道怎么去爱你
Even if it means she doesn't know how to love you.
丹尼斯只是希望
I think all Dennis wants is
你能回到克里斯汀身边
Just for you to be in Christine's life again.
我也希望这样
That's what I want, too.
谢谢你
Thank you.
希望这是你的心愿
I hope this is what you wanted.
这是你的心愿  对吧
This is what you wanted, right?
-是的  -你准备好了吗
- Right.  - Are you ready to go?
-去哪  -走进光里  你依然看不见吗
- Where?  - Into the light. Can't you still see it?
-我看见太阳  -不是太阳  那是光
- Mm-hmm. I see the sun.  - No, not the sun. The light.
太阳就是那道光
The sun is the light.
你看见那道光了
I thought you could see the light.
你还有什么需要我帮你的吗
Is there something else than I can help you with?
你知道爱是什么  什么是爱
You know what love is. What is love?
是什么感觉
What does it feel like?
丹尼斯  你帮助莉斯和克里斯汀重聚
Dennis, what you did to bring Liz and Christine together,
这就是爱
That's what love is.
说什么不重要  重要的是行动
It's not about what we say. It's about what we do.